Dean Hamann

https://dhamann1.github.io/Dean_Portfolio/ https://www.linkedin.com/in/hamanndean/ https://github.com/dhamann1 Los Angeles, CA (949) 939-4973 hamann.dean@gmail.com

Summary

I'm a Web Developer working in the MERN Stack, Ruby on Rails, and JavaScript. Previously I worked as a Business Development Rep / Digital Marketing Analyst. I enjoyed collaborating with engineers in order to provide technical demonstrations that matched potential clients needs. Being a BDR taught me the ability to initiate and drive projects to completion with minimal guidance and to apply new skill sets in fast-paced environments. Currently I'm working on a MERN stack application that allows you to search for movies.

Technical Skills / Frameworks:

MongoDB Express
React Node.js
Ruby on Rails JavaScript

Projects:

FilmPicks

FilmPicks is an application that allows users to search and favorite movies through The Movie Database (TMDb) API. The app was built using the MERN (MongoDB, Express, React, Node.js) Stack.

WeMeet

WeMeet is an application allows people to create and join events based on certain interests and discuss with other users about the event. WeMeet was built using Ruby on Rails and Bootstrap.

Don't Think, Just Eat

Don't Think, Just Eat is an application allows users to select a restaurant within their specified location. Users are able to bookmark their favorite restaurants they've visited and save notes for future reference. The app utilizes both the Yelp and Google Maps API. I helped with creating the controller actions that performed CRUD and consuming the third-party APIs. DTJE was built using MongoDB, Express, Node, Javascript and Materialize.

Simpsons Blackjack

A Simpsons themed blackjack game that allows you to play against the dealer. This game was built using JavaScript and jQuery.

Experience

BDR - Enterprise Sales / Digital Marketing Analyst - *StackIQ*, March 2016 - July 2017
Digital Marketing Analyst - *Quad2Media*, August 2015 - February 2016
Service Coordinator Intern - *Worldlink Integration Group*, July 2015 - August 2015
File Clerk - *Carno & Carlton, LLP*, July 2013 - April 2015
Collections Intern - *Casa Dolores, Center of the Popular Arts of Mexico*, January 2014 - March 2014

Education

B.A. Psychology, University of California, Santa Barbara, Sept 2010 - March 2014 General Assembly, Web Development Immersive, Sept 2017 - Dec 2017